(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-15T14:19:51.277068",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
本日は 尾丸ポルカ 3周年活動記念ライブ「POLPOLPOLKA！」にご来場いただき
Thank you very much for attending today's Omaru Polka 3rd Anniversary Live,
誠にありがとうございます。
"POLPOLPOLKA!"
開演に先立ちまして
Before the show begins,
お客様にいくつかお願いがございます。
we have a few requests for our audience.
しゃべります。
I'll speak.
スマートフォン、パソコン越しでのご声援、
Cheers through smartphones and PCs,
スクリーンショット、
screenshots,
大きな音を出しての応援など大歓迎でございます。
and cheering with loud sounds are very much welcome!
おのおの好きな形ででお楽しみ下さるようお願い申し上げます。
Please enjoy it however you like.
また本公演ではたくさんのゲストの方々もいらっしゃいます。
Also, in this performance, we have many guest appearances.
その方々のファンのみなさまもぜひスクリーンショットを撮影してハッシュタグ#尾丸ポルカ3周年をつけポストしていただけますと幸いです。
We would appreciate it if fans of those guests could also take screenshots and post them with the hashtag #OmaruPolka3Anniversary.
ライブ本編の時間は1時間を想定しております。
The live main show is expected to last for one hour.
事前収録での公演となりますが万が一トラブルが発生した際には迅速に対応いたしますのでストリーミングは開いたままポストや固定コメントでのご連絡をお待ちください。
This performance is pre-recorded, but in the unlikely event of trouble, we will respond promptly, so please leave streaming open and wait for contact via posts or pinned comments.
重ねてのご案内になりますが本日のハッシュタグは#尾丸ポルカ3周年になります。
To reiterate, today's hashtag is #OmaruPolka3Anniversary.
3は英数字の3になります。
The "3" is the alphanumeric number 3.
是非今一度皆様で「いくぞー」とともにポストをしていただけますと幸いです。
We would appreciate it if you could post once again together with everyone saying "Let's go!"
それでは準備はよろしいでしょうか？
Now then, are you ready?
ポストの準備ができた方はテンカウントでお願いいたします。
If you are ready with your posts, please join the countdown.
10、9、8、7、6、5、4、3、2、1、0！
10, 9, 8, 7, 6, 5, 4, 3, 2, 1, 0!
ポルカ3周年行くぞー！
Omaru Polka 3rd Anniversary, let's go!
ありがとうございます！皆様自分たちとポストされた皆様に拍手をどうかお送りください！
Thank you very much! Everyone, please give a round of applause to yourselves and everyone who posted!
チャット欄の皆様方におかれましてはこちらもテンカウントでポルカオルカとチャットしていただけますと幸いです。
For those in the chat, we would appreciate it if you could also chat "Polka Olka" in a countdown.
それではいきますよ。10、9、8、7、6、5、4、3、2、1、0！ポルカオルカ！
Here we go. 10, 9, 8, 7, 6, 5, 4, 3, 2, 1, 0! Polka Olka!
おや、どこからかおるような元気な声が。
Oh, I hear energetic voices coming from somewhere.
それでは開演まで今しばらくお待ちください。
Now then, please wait a little longer until the show begins.
Hello! Hello! Everyone!
まもなく On Stage!
On stage shortly!
嘘か本当か感じて さあ始めよう!
Feel if it's a lie or truth, now let's begin!
遅くなりましたがポルカ3周年記念ライブ
Sorry to keep you waiting, welcome to Polka's
ポルポルポルカへようこそ!
3rd Anniversary Live Pol Pol Polka!
最後まで楽しんでいってください!
Please enjoy it all the way to the end!
ようこそParty Night
Welcome to Party Night,
誰かが語る
someone tells a tale.
連日満員御礼
Packed house every day,
どうぞご贔屓に
thank you for your continued patronage.
待ってたShow Time
Waiting for Show Time,
誰かが語る
someone tells a tale.
どうでもいいような顔を見せてよねHa-ha!
Show us a nonchalant face, ha-ha!
悪巧み、全店、並べたなら一網打尽
Schemes, all shops, lined up for a clean sweep.
ふざけちゃいませんか？
Is this not a joke?
今、辿り着いた
Now, I've reached
憧れの世界
the world of admiration.
ここはまるでペテン師の楽園
Here is just like a swindler's paradise.
吐き気を飲み込む
Swallowing down the nausea.
転換、幕が開けた其の夜の纏め
Intermission, the curtain rose on that night's summary.
着飾る人形はピエロに口づけを
The dressed-up doll kisses the pierrot.
本日大団円 脚本が笑う
Today's grand finale, the script laughs.
騙されてくれるあなたこそ
You are the one who lets yourself be fooled.
アタシ今ここで何をしてる?
What am I doing right here and now?
盛り上がっていくぞ! 手拍子お願いしまーす!
Let's pump it up! Round of applause, please!
Clap your hands! 行きまーす!
Clap your hands! Here we go!
耳をつんざく
Deafening
拍手喝采
applause and cheers.
サルもおだてればヒトにもなれる
Even a monkey can become human if flattered.
フォーカスされた日常
The focused everyday life.
心中するように
Just as if committing a double suicide in a dream...
一回、二回、三回、嘘を重ねて
One time, two times, three times, piling up the lies,
十回、千回、億回、目を逸らして
Turning back, turning back, turning back, turning back, closing my eyes and turning a blind eye.
あれ？なんだっけ？アタシは誰？
Huh? What was it again? Who am I?
もううんざりした仮面舞踏会
Already fed up with this masked masquerade.
とりとめのないワルツでお出迎え、展覧会の中
Greeting the waltz with meaningless faces, inside the exhibition.
曝け出させて、曝け出させてよ、アタシの世界は
Let me see it, let me see it. My world is...
ぐるぐるぐるぐるぐるぐるぐるぐる回ってく
Spinning, spinning, spinning, spinning, spinning, spinning round and round!
幕が開けたそのオノマトペ、群がる人形はダリアの花束を
Curtain is up, onomatopoeia, the swarming dolls holding bouquets of dahlias.
選んでくれた服を着て踊りましょう
Let's dance in the clothes chosen for me.
騙されてくれる貴方達と、いい加減もう
And with the people who let themselves be deceived, good grief.
これが好きだったんだろ？
Is this all you wanted?
振り落とせペルソナを
Shake off your persona!
とうとう終わった 悲劇を喜劇化してさあ
Finally, it's over, turning tragedy into a farce,
(今日も普通に楽しかったよ)
(Well, it was fun as usual.)
さあ褒めちぎってくれよ
Please praise me!
本当の僕はアタシじゃないから
Because the real me isn't me,
(今日も普通に楽しかったよ)
(It was fun as usual today.)
幕が閉じたそのオノマトペ
The onomatopoeia when the curtain closed,
着替え人形、別れのアンコール
Dressed-up dolls, an encore of separation.
本日も大団円、脚本が笑う
Today as well, a happy ending, the script laughs.
どうしようもないよな、ああ、
What should I do? No way, ah...
「調子に乗るなよ」と、ただ一回言ってくれ
"Don't get full of yourself," just say it to me once.
そういや夢も散々言ってとら
"Yeah, well, dreams also fade," you used to say,
「もう後戻りは叶わない」と、気付けばそこには一人で
"There's no turning back anymore," and before you know it, you're all alone.
ヌララヌララヌララヌララヌラヌルリラ、ミラミレズジルババラリラ
Nuralanuralanuralanuralanururira, miramirezujiruba barira...
...バリルラールララシタバルラリ、ノリレルラールラ
...barurarasu barurari, norirerura...
まもなく開演の時間です
Before long, the time of performance...
この物語はフィクションです。
This performance is a fiction.
これは可愛いお嬢さん
This is an adorable young lady.
真っ白な毛がとても素敵ね
Pure white fur is also very lovely.
こんな月が綺麗な夜は僕と一緒に遊びませんか
Won't you play with me on such a beautiful moonlit night?
ニャン生は一度きり
Cat life is only once,
楽しむが勝ちなのです！
Enjoying it is winning!
これは可愛いお嬢さん
This is a cute young lady,
真っ白な毛がとても素敵ね
your pure white fur is so lovely.
こんな月が綺麗な夜は
On such a beautiful moonlit night,
僕と一緒に遊びませんか
won't you come play with me?
ニャン生は一度きり
A cat's life is only once,
楽しむが勝ちなのです
so winning is having fun.
あなたを縛る首輪は
The collar that binds you,
噛み千切ってあげましょう
I'll bite right through it for you!
野良は最高ニャンニャンニャン
Stray cats are the best, meow, meow, meow!
魚くすねて、ハト追いかけて
Stealing fish and chasing pigeons,
昼間は働く人間を尻目に
right under the noses of working humans,
屋根の上で夢うつつ
half-asleep on rooftops in a daze.
あなたも自由にニャンニャンニャン
You can be free too, meow, meow, meow!
素敵な仲間も紹介しましょう
Let me introduce you to wonderful friends.
さあ、その窓を開いて
Come on, open that window
飛び出すのです！
and leap right out!
これは気まぐれな野良猫さん
This is a carefree stray cat,
闇の中目だけが光ってる
only your eyes are glowing in the dark.
随分口が上手だけど
You've got a smooth tongue,
私はバカな女じゃないわ
but I'm not a foolish woman.
ニャン生は一度きり
A cat's life is only once,
だからこそ飼われるのよ
that's why I'm kept as a pet.
ブランド首輪の価値が
Do you understand the value
あなたには分かるかしら？
of a brand-name collar?
私は優雅よニャンニャンニャン
I am elegant, meow, meow, meow.
美味しい食事にふかふかベッド
Delicious meals and a fluffy bed,
水はちょっぴり苦手だけど
I'm a little bit bad with water,
毎日シャワーだって浴びれるの
but I get to take a shower every day.
それに比べてニャンニャンニャン
Compared to that, meow, meow, meow,
あなたは誰に守ってもらうの？
who is going to protect you?
明日車にひかれるかも
You might get run over by a car tomorrow,
知れないじゃない！
who knows!
そんな強気なところも素敵です
Even that strong-willed side of you is lovely,
一層あなたを好きになりました
and I've come to like you even more.
あら正直ね、でもそんなやり方じゃ
My, how honest, but with an approach like that,
ココロ揺らがないわ
my heart won't be swayed.
僕の夢はニャンニャンニャン
My dream is, meow, meow, meow,
いつかはこの街を飛び出して
to someday leap out of this town,
はるか北の国に旅して
journey to the far northern land,
オーロラをこの目で見ることです
and see the aurora with my own eyes.
そこにあなたがニャンニャンニャン
If you were there, meow, meow, meow,
居てくれたらなんて素敵でしょう
how wonderful that would be.
だけどそれは叶わないらしい
But it seems that won't come true...
生き方はニャンニャンニャン
My way of life is, meow, meow, meow,
そう簡単には変えないの
can't be changed so easily.
それに私を飼っている
Besides, I cannot leave
女の子一人にできないわ
the girl who keeps me all alone.
話の途中よニャンニャンニャン
We're in the middle of talking, meow, meow, meow!
あらもう行っちゃうの？ねぇちょっと！
Oh, are you leaving already? Hey, wait!
明日もここに来ていいのよ
It's okay for you to come here tomorrow too,
待ってるから
because I'll be waiting...
僕の夢はニャンニャンニャン
My dream is, meow, meow, meow,
いつかはこの街を飛び出して
to someday leap out of this town,
はるか北の国に旅して
journey to the far northern land,
オーロラをこの目で見ることです
and see the aurora with my own eyes.
そこにあなたがニャンニャンニャン
If you were there, meow, meow, meow,
居てくれたらなんて素敵でしょう
how wonderful that would be.
だけどそれは叶わないらしい
But it seems that won't come true...
生き方はニャンニャンニャン
My way of life is, meow, meow, meow,
そう簡単には変えられないの
can't be changed so easily.
それに私を飼っている
Besides, I cannot leave
女の子一人にできないわ
the girl who keeps me all alone.
話の途中よニャンニャンニャン
We're in the middle of talking, meow, meow, meow!
あらもう行っちゃうの？ねぇちょっと！
Oh, are you leaving already? Hey, wait!
明日もここに来ていいのよ
It's okay for you to come here tomorrow too,
待ってるから
because I'll be waiting...
そんな強気なところも素敵です
Even that strong-willed side of you is lovely,
一層あなたを好きになりました
and I've come to like you even more.
あら正直ね、でもそんなやり方じゃ
My, how honest, but with an approach like that,
ココロ揺らがないわ
my heart won't be swayed.
いや、やっぱり猫は難しい。もう猫はやめるにゃん。
Man, cats are tough. I'm quitting being a cat, meow.
どうしたんですか、ポルカ先輩？
What's wrong, Polka-senpai?
ああ！そこにいるのはバリバリで仕事できる女幹部のご隠居じゃないか！ホロクスの調子ははどうだい？
Ah! Isn't that the hardcore, career-woman executive retiree?! How's HoloX doing?
はい、今日も仕事100件こなして来ましたよ。
Yep, I finished 100 jobs today too.
す、それならば教えてくれないか。あの……女の子を優しくこういざなうすべを……ね？
I-If so, could you tell me? Um... how to gently court a girl... you know?
それならポルカ先輩、私たちで王様になりましょう。
Well then, Polka-senpai, let's become royalty together.
それはかなり……急だな。
That's, like... pretty sudden.
髭男くらいがこれから流行りますから！
Official HIGE DANdism style is gonna be all the rage!
確かに？仕事100件こなして来ましたから！確かに？
Really? Since I finished 100 jobs! Really?
さあ、行きますよ！一緒にジュリエットを迎えに行きましょう！
Now, let's go! Let's go meet Juliet together!
お、俺の……ジュリエット……
M-My... Juliet...
初めまして お嬢さん 西の国から
A pleasure to meet you, my lady, from western lands
愛のために貴女に会いに来ました
I've come to meet you for the sake of love.
急な話ですがどうか驚かないで
It's a sudden talk, but please don't be surprised.
僕のお姫様にね なってください
Please become my princess.
悩んでるの？ お嬢さん 浮かない顔は
Are you worried, my lady? That gloomy face
悩みがない顔は
A face with no worries
似合わないよ ほらほら 耳を貸してよ
doesn't suit you, hey, hey, lend me your ear.
もしも宜しければですが 俺と一緒に
If it's alright with you, won't you come with me
全て捨てて逃げよう 東の国へ
leaving everything behind for the eastern lands?
寂しそうなその紅い唇に
On those lonely, crimson lips,
優しい魔法かけるよ
I will cast a gentle spell.
さあさドレスに着替えて
Come now, change into a dress,
世界一のお姫様 踊りましょうか？
finest princess in the world, shall we dance?
誰もが貴方を欲しがって 僕らを夢中にさせちゃって
Everyone desires you, making us lose our minds,
奪うよ愛のkiss
stealing a kiss of love.
瞳閉じてプレゼント
Close your eyes, here's a present,
空に光るあの星を二人のものに
making that star shining in the sky ours.
世界が貴方を欲しがって 俺たち本気にさせちゃって
The world desires you, making us truly serious,
その名はジュリエッタ
and your name is Juliet.
命に代えても守り抜いてみせます さあおいで
Even if it costs my life, I will protect you, so come here.
後悔はさせない色褪せない景色へ さあ おいで
I won't let you regret it, to an unfading scenery, come along.
選んで？
Choose?
渡したくない他の誰かには譲れないのさ 誰にも
I won't hand you over to anyone else, I won't surrender you to anyone.
さあさ裸足で駆け出せ
Come now, run out barefoot,
世界一のお姫様 夢の世界へ
finest princess in the world, to a world of dreams!
不安な思いは消し去って ちょっぴりルール破っちゃって
Wipe away all your anxieties, break the rules a little,
狙うよ愛のkiss
aiming for a kiss of love.
手を繋いで連れてくよ
I'll take your hand and lead you away,
海に眠る宝石を二人のものに
making the jewels sleeping in the sea ours.
世界が貴方を欲しがって 僕らを本気にさせちゃって
The world desires you, making us truly serious,
その名はジュリエッタ
and your name is Juliet.
貴方の事しか見えなくて 僕らの本気を見せちゃって
Seeing nothing but you, showing you how serious we are,
その名はジュリエッタ
and your name is Juliet.
靴の底がすり減ってる
The soles of my shoes are worn down,
まるで今のココロみたい…
just like my heart right now...
他人と深く分かり合うって難しいと感じたよ
I felt that it's difficult to truly understand others deeply.
うなずく事しかできない自分嫌いになってる
I'm starting to hate myself for only being able to nod along.
世の中には思い通りいかないことあるけれど
In this world, there are things that don't go as planned,
落ち込むだけ落ち込んだら笑ってまた歩かなきゃ
but after being as down as I can be, I have to smile and walk again.
だけどゆずれない大切な物は守りととおしたい
Yet, I want to protect the precious things I cannot compromise on.
ユメ実現するための犠牲はもうヤダよ
I'm done with sacrifices just to make dreams come true.
気持ちに嘘つくようなことはやめてYESのイイコは卒業しよう
Stop lying to your feelings, let's graduate from being a submissive 'good girl'.
そうすればきっと自分のことをスキになれるはずだよ
If you do that, you should surely be able to love yourself.
強気でいこう
Let's go with confidence!
一目惚れで恋におちた彼とは2年たったけど
It's been two years since I fell in love at first sight with him,
ドアを閉めた音でわかる もうだめだね私達
but I can tell by the sound of the door closing, we're done for.
誰かと私の間を行ったり来たりしてると気づいていたけどひとりになるのが怖かった
I had noticed him going back and forth between someone else and me, but I was afraid of being alone.
魂を売るようなことはやめて都合のイイコは卒業しよう
Stop selling your soul, let's graduate from being a convenient girl.
迷いのある人生だっていい
Even a life full of hesitation is fine.
どんな悩みだって
Whatever worries there are,
超えてみせる
I'll overcome them!
嫌われたくない想いが
The desire not to be disliked
自由の羽根 踏みつけた
trampled on the wings of freedom.
飛べないまま終わりたくない
I don't want to end without being able to fly,
想いのまま生きていたい
I want to live just as I feel.
気持ちに嘘をつくような事はやめて
Stop telling lies to your feelings,
YESのイイコは卒業しよう
Let's graduate from being the obedient "yes" girl.
そうすればきっと自分のことをスキになれるはずだよ
If you do, surely you'll be able to love yourself.
強気で行こう
Let's go with confidence!
迷いのある人生だっていいよ
A life with doubts is just fine,
どんな悩みだって
whatever worries there are.
超えてみせる
I'll overcome them!
たった一人しかいない自分スキになろう
Let's love ourselves, the only one and only self!
ポルカ…
Polka...
ヌーベ、いいよね？
Nube, is that alright?
船長…来てくれたのか
Captain... you came for me?
そうだよポルカ！船長もポルカと歌いたいなって思ったんだ！
That's right, Polka! Captain wanted to sing with Polka too!
ありがとう船長！やっぱりアニソンって最高だよな！
Thank you, Captain! Anime songs are simply the best!
あの、ポルカさ、ずっと歌いたかった曲があるんだけど、えー…一緒に歌ってくれてもいいかな？
Um, Polka, there's a song I've always wanted to sing... um, would you mind singing it with me?
いいよポルカ！歌ってあげるよ！優しいな！なんかセリフとかも言っちゃっていいかな？セリフにも乗っちゃっていいかな？
Sure, Polka! I'll sing with you! How kind! Can I say some lines too? Can I hop on the narration too?
いいよポルカ！今日は全肯定してあげるよ！やったぜ！聞いてください。「Get along」！
Sure, Polka! Today I'll affirm everything for you! Yay! Please listen to "Get along"!
立ち向かう先に乾いた風
Head towards the dry wind ahead,
激しく吹き荒れても
even if it blows fiercely.
呪文の一つも唱えたなら
If you can cast even a single spell,
私のペースになる
it will become my own pace.
誰もがうらやむこのパワーと
Everyone envies this power,
美貌が許さないわ
and my beauty won't allow it.
どんな相手でもひるまないで
No matter the opponent, don't flinch,
マントをなびかせるの
let your cape flutter in the wind.
あれもしたいこれもしたい
I want this, I want that too,
油断したら地獄行きよ
If you let your guard down, it's straight to hell!
女の子に見えたって
even if I look like a girly girl.
邪魔はさせないから
I won't let anyone get in my way.
Far away 思うまま我がままに
Far away, living as I please and want,
旅を続けて行きたい
I want to continue my journey.
辛い日々も笑顔でピリオドよ
Even on tough days, put a smile on as a period.
Far away 幾つもの魔力抱いて
Far away, embracing countless magical powers,
今日を越えて行きたいの
I want to surpass today and go on.
未来に向かい 歩き続けて行く
Walking on towards the future, step by step.
限りないほど Get along, Try again
To no end, Get along, Try again.
退屈な時は悪い奴ら
When bored, target the bad guys
ターゲットに気晴らし
and take it out on them for some fun!
ストレスも飛んでお宝まで手に入れればやめられない
Stress flies away, and once you get the treasure, you can't stop!
お気楽にちょっと遊ぶ度に満たされた気分だわ
Every time I play around carefree, I feel so fulfilled.
スリリングな日のエッセンスは美味しくなくちゃダメね
The essence of thrilling days has to be delicious!
あれも欲しいこれも欲しい
I want this, I want that too,
女の子は欲張りよ
girls are greedy after all.
生きる事は綺麗事じゃ通り抜けられない
Living life isn't something you can breeze through just with ideals.
Far away 思うまま我がままに
Far away, living as I please and want,
旅を続けて行きたい
I want to continue my journey.
辛い日々も笑顔でピリオドよ
Even on tough days, put a smile on as a period.
Far away 何時でも独りじゃない
Far away, you're never alone anytime.
力合わせ、遥か先
Joining forces, far ahead,
未来に向かい 歩き続けて行く
walking on towards the future.
限りないほど Get along, Try again
To no end, Get along, Try again.
Far away 思うまま我がままに
Far away, acting on my own selfish desires,
旅を続けて行きたい
I want to continue this journey.
辛い日々も笑顔でピリオドよ
Even painful days will end with a smile, like a period on a sentence.
Far away 幾つの魔力抱いて今日を越えて行きたいの
Far away, embracing countless magical powers, I want to surpass today and move forward.
未来に向かい歩き続けて行く
Walking on towards the future.
Far away 何時でも独りじゃない力合わせ、遥か先
Far away, we're never alone, combining our strengths far into the distance.
未来に向かい歩き続けて行く
Walking on towards the future.
限りないほど Get along, Try again
Without end, Get along, Try again.
スマイル スマイル スマイル
Smile, smile, smile.
どんな笑顔見せても
No matter what kind of smile I show you,
心の中が読まれそう
It's as if you can read right through my heart.
大人ぶった下手な笑顔じゃ心かくせない
With this awkward, forced adult smile, I can't hide my true feelings.
大キライ 大キライ 大キライ 大スキ
I hate you, I hate you, I hate you, I love you!
季節を感じてサマーナイト
Feeling the season in a summer night,
いつも二人でいたいの
I always want to be with you.
わがままなんかは言わないだけど二人でいたいの
I won't say anything selfish, but I just want to be with you,
なんか変な感じ
With this strange feeling.
去年はどの娘とサマーナイトどんな風に過ごしたの
Who were you with last year on a summer night, and how did you spend it?
ジェラシーなんかは感じないただのヤキモチだから矛盾だらけ
I'm not jealous, it's just a bit of possessiveness, full of contradictions.
私の中に私がいるわカワイくなれない私
There is a "me" inside of me, a "me" that can't act cute,
あなたの腕に飛び込めなくて
Unable to jump into your arms,
スネたり泣いたりして
Pouting and crying.
スマイル スマイル スマイル
Smile, smile, smile.
くちびる見つめないで
Don't stare at my lips like that,
心の中が読まれそう
It's as if you can read right through my heart.
大人ぶった下手なメイクじゃ心かくせない
With this awkward makeup, I can't hide my true feelings.
大キライ 大キライ 大キライ 大スキ
I hate you, I hate you, I hate you, I love you!
どこでもいいけど Drivin' 行った事ないトコがいい
Anywhere is fine, Drivin', to a place we've never been.
別に迷ってもかまわないあなたも知らないトコロ
It's fine even if we get lost, to a place even you don't know.
本当変な私 お祈りしたのよ Oh My God
I really am strange, I prayed, Oh My God,
もっと近づける様に
So I could get a little closer to you.
二人の年の差をもっと近づく様に
Closing the gap between our ages, Oh My God,
Ah 無理な話
Ah, what an impossible talk.
あなたの中の私はどこよ
Where is the "me" inside of you?
早くクリックしてみて
Try clicking on it quickly,
南の島の空の鳥みたいにあなたに浮かんでみたい
Like a bird in the southern skies, I want to float right in you.
スマイル スマイル スマイル
Smile, smile, smile.
どんな笑顔見せても
No matter what kind of smile I show you,
心の中が読まれそう
It's as if you can read right through my heart.
大人ぶった下手な笑顔じゃ心かくせない
With this awkward, forced adult smile, I can't hide my true feelings.
大キライ 大キライ 大キライ 大スキ
I hate you, I hate you, I hate you, I love you!
くちびる見つめないで
Don't stare at my lips like that,
心の中が読まれそう
It's as if you can read right through my heart.
大人ぶった下手なメイクじゃ心かくせない
With this awkward makeup, I can't hide my true feelings.
大キライ 大キライ
I hate you, I hate you!
大キライ
I hate you.
大スキ
I love you.
大キライ
I hate you.
大好きだよ。
I love you so much.
でも「大嫌い」って言ってたじゃん。
But you said you hated me.
こういうのは駆け引きなんだよ。
This kind of thing is all about playing games.
そうだよ。
That's right.
でも求めてるのはセクシーな感じだから。
But what we're looking for is a sexy vibe.
大好きだよって、みんなに愛を込めて言うんだよ。
Saying "I love you" with love to everyone.
メルも、みんなのこと大好き！
Mel loves everyone so much too!
メル、なんだか熱くなってきたきちゃった。
Mel, I'm starting to feel kind of hot.
はぁ、確かに。
Hah, true.
なんかお腹空いてきちゃった。
I'm starting to get hungry.
あきちゃん。
Aki-chan.
あっちの涼しいところに二人で行こっか。
Let's go somewhere cool together over there.
今夜は返さないよ。
I won't let you go tonight.
メル、あ、え、ちょっと。
Mel, ah, um, wait.
なんだろ、ものすご、すごく、えっちあー…
What is this... so, so... ecchi...
新しい世界が開けた気がするなぁ。
I feel like a whole new world has opened up.
おまる、これ見て！カブトムシ！
Omaru, look at this! A rhinoceros beetle!
おい、てめぇ！それペコちゃんがみつけたやつ！
Hey, you bastard! That's the one Peko-chan found!
一気に小学生になったな。
You went straight to being an elementary schooler.
おいおい、ボンバーしようぜ、ボンバー！
Hey hey, let's go bomber, bomber!
ボンバー、ペコか？
Bomber, peko?
うそ、な、ペコちゃんも気になるペコね。
No way, Peko-chan is curious too, peko.
ごめん待って、全然聞いてなかったんだけど、ボンバーって何？
Sorry wait, I wasn't listening at all, but what is "bomber"?
だから、マジでボンバーするってことだよ。
It means we're seriously going to bomber!
ポルカちゃん、わかってないペコね。
Polka-chan, you don't get it, peko.
つまりは、マジボンバーペコ！
In other words, it's seriously bomber, peko!
ボンバーペコ？
Bomber, peko?
本気ボンバー!!
Honki Bomber!!
夏じゃん 見上げる空 青い海 wow wow wow
It's summer! Looking up at the sky, the blue sea, wow wow wow
自由に描こう 僕がルール
Draw it freely, I make the rules
OH YEAH!
夏じゃん 大きくなれ マジボンバー wow wow wow
It's summer! Grow big, seriously bomber, wow wow wow
好奇心のまま GO!
Go with your curiosity!
熱くなれ
Get fired up!
遊びも100点 学びも100点
100 points in play, 100 points in study!
時間いっぱい
Time is full
手を抜かない ボンバー
Don't hold back, bomber!
くじ運のせいにゃ絶対しねぇ
Don't ever blame your luck!
そもそも人生チョイスの連続
Life is a continuous series of choices!
頼れる奴 キザな奴 wow wow wow
Reliable guys, cheesy guys, wow wow wow
いろいろ出会い 僕が育つ
Meeting all kinds of people helps me grow
OH YEAH! 夏じゃん 成長しろ マジボンバー wow wow wow
OH YEAH! It's summer! Grow up, seriously bomber, wow wow wow
世界みんなでPeace! 立ち上がれ!
Peace to everyone in the world! Stand up!
涙も出る 拍手もする
Tears fall, applause rings out
ほめてほめられ やる気も出る ボンバー
Praising and being praised boosts motivation, bomber!
カブトムシだって 夢があるだろう
Even rhinoceros beetles have dreams, right?
いつかは大空の彼方 HOP STEP JUMP!
Someday beyond the open sky, HOP STEP JUMP!
夏じゃん 見上げる空 青い海 wow wow wow
It's summer! Looking up at the sky, the blue sea, wow wow wow
自由に描こう 僕がルール
Draw it freely, I make the rules
OH YEAH! 夏じゃん 大きくなれ マジボンバー wow wow wow
OH YEAH! It's summer! Grow big, seriously bomber, wow wow wow
好奇心のまま GO! 熱くなれ
Go with your curiosity! Get fired up!
夏じゃん 頼れる奴 キザな奴 wow wow wow
It's summer! Reliable guys, cheesy guys, wow wow wow
いろいろ出会い 僕が育つ
Meeting all kinds of people helps me grow
OH YEAH! 夏じゃん 成長しろ マジボンバー wow wow wow
OH YEAH! It's summer! Grow up, seriously bomber, wow wow wow
世界みんなでPeace! 立ち上がれ!
Peace to everyone in the world! Stand up!
夏じゃん 見上げる空 青い海 wow wow wow
It's summer! Looking up at the sky, the blue sea, wow wow wow
自由に描こう 僕がルール
Draw it freely, I make the rules
OH YEAH! 夏じゃん 大きくなれ マジボンバー wow wow wow
OH YEAH! It's summer! Grow big, seriously bomber, wow wow wow
好奇心のまま GO! 熱くなれ
Go with your curiosity! Get fired up!
今日もなんだか一日楽しくて
Today too, somehow the whole day was fun,
君とずっと笑い合っていたよね
and you and I were always laughing together, right?
どんな嫌なことがあっても
No matter what unpleasant things happen,
すぐにパッと忘れちゃったほうがいいから
it's better to just forget them right away.
時々泣いちゃう私も涙の分だけ
Sometimes I cry too, but for every tear I shed,
きっと強くなっていけるはず
I'm sure I can grow stronger.
そう信じているから
Because I believe that.
元気いっぱい私に
"Hello to my energetic self,
ハローそのままいいよって
stay just as you are,"
楽しもうよこのまま
Let's enjoy it just like this,
ハロー私のライフ
hello to my life!
そうよもっと私にハロー笑顔でいたいから
That's right, hello to wanting to smile even more,
晴れた空見上げて
Looking up at the clear sky,
ハロー笑顔のサイン
hello, the sign of a smile!
一分一秒この瞬間も
Every single minute, every second of this moment
楽しいことばかり続くエブリデイ
is an everyday full of fun things.
君とケンカすることもあるけど
Though we sometimes argue, too,
すぐにちゃんと仲直りもできるから
we can always make up properly right away.
辛いことも悲しいこともたまにはあるけど
Though painful and sad things happen sometimes,
すぐに乗り越えていけるはず
we'll surely overcome them right away.
大丈夫前を向いていこうよ
It's okay, let's look forward!
キラキラ輝いてる
Sparkling brightly,
ハロー虹色の毎日
hello, rainbow-colored days!
笑い声溢れる
Overflowing with laughter,
ハロー私のライフ
hello to my life!
明日も明後日もハロー
Tomorrow and the day after too, hello,
笑顔でいたいから
because I want to keep smiling,
眩しい青空にハロー
Hello to the dazzling blue sky,
笑顔のサイン
the sign of a smile!
元気いっぱい私に
"Hello to my energetic self,
ハローそのままいいよって
stay just as you are,"
楽しもうよこのまま
Let's enjoy it just like this,
ハロー私のライフ
hello to my life!
そうよもっと私にハロー笑顔でいたいから
That's right, hello to wanting to smile even more,
晴れた空見上げて
Looking up at the clear sky,
ハロー笑顔のサイン
hello, the sign of a smile!
先輩、やっぱり夏は暑いっすね！
Senpai, summer is really hot after all!
暑いも何も激熱だよ！
Hot? This is scorching hot!
激熱っすか？
Scorching hot?
坂本もなんかテンションアップしてきました！
Sakamoto's got their tension boosted too!
マジ？ポルカもさ、ここまでのラッシュで覚醒しちゃった！
Seriously? Polka's totally awakened with this rush up to here!
だから坂本は召集されたんですね。
That's why Sakamoto was summoned, huh?
それじゃあネクストターーーーーン！おお、継続だ！
Then, next turn! Oh, it continues!
Enter the stage!!
栄光への扉が開いた　雲一つない晴天
The door to glory has opened, cloudless clear skies,
絶好の完勝日和を light up
A perfect day for absolute victory, light up!
手招いてる Game board
The game board is beckoning.
今日の相棒 It's alright
Today's partner? It's alright.
お前が天使でも悪魔でもいいだろう
Angel or devil, either is fine.
主導権はあくまでも Me, boy?
The initiative is still mine, boy?
上限 MAX 3枚のコインで Bet
Betting with a maximum of three coins.
でも浮き足立ってる訳じゃなく基本は DDT
Not getting carried away, basically it's DDT!
「そう信じる者は救われる」
"He who believes will be saved,"
「この俺ならきっと報われる」
"For someone like me, surely rewarded,"
疑いもしない幼気な瞳を光らせてるハイエナ
Hyenas shining innocent eyes without a single doubt!
一か八か乗るか反るか
All or nothing, sink or swim,
派手に大博打
A flashy, high-stakes gamble!
吉か凶か半かチョか
Fortune or misfortune, even or odd,
勝てば So バブリー
Winning makes it so bubbly!
成功か迷走か一歩違えばゲームオーバー
Success or wandering off, one wrong step and game over!
I am foolish?
へぇそうかならぶっ壊すよ定常は
Heh, is that so? Then I'll shatter the status quo.
Make some noise!! 鳴り響く勝利のファンファーレ
Make some noise!! The triumphant fanfare echoes.
これぞ Roman of the man 最後にとり笑うのは誰?
This is a man's romance. Who'll have the last laugh?
let's get it 夢の 3$EVEN
Let's get it, the dream's 3$EVEN!
目もくらむほど Big Money, Money, Money
Dazzling enough to blind you, big money, money, money!
Go to the Hell or Heaven?
運命の行方は Nobody knows
Where fate leads, nobody knows.
SEVEN SEVEN Cherry
現実(リアル)は Heavy 泡のように消えてく Money, Money, Money
Reality is heavy, vanishing like bubbles—money, money, money!
Gimme Gimme 夢の 3$EVEN
Gimme gimme, the dream's 3$EVEN!
神様 俺様 My god, My god, My god
God, myself, my god, my god, my god!
Are you ready to continue? 頭ん中 響く 10カウント
Are you ready to continue? A ten-count echoes in my mind.
焦らせるグラビラ むずいギャンブラ 言うまでもなく let's get down
Hurry up gravira, tricky gambler, needless to say, let's get down!
七転八倒でも立ち上がるのが男ってもんだぜ
Standing back up after every fall is what a real man does.
一見さんのビギナーズラック狙いが入る土俵じゃねえ
This isn't a ring for beginners chasing beginner's luck.
一花咲かすまで Yen 稼ぐだけ 迷ってる暇もねえな
Just earning cash until we bloom, no time to hesitate.
play the game このスリルさえ Entertain だぜ 何度も again and again
Play the game, even this thrill is entertainment—over and over.
全ツッパ目前 ピンチも作戦通り お決まりのヒーロー大逆転
All-in approaching, even a pinch goes as planned, the classic comeback.
サクセスストーリー
A success story!
一か八か乗るか反るか すべて風任せ
All or nothing, sink or swim, leave it all to the wind.
吉か凶か半かチョか 今が肝心要の抗争か？
Good or bad luck, even or odd—now is the critical clash?
逃走か？闘争か？ギリギリ気持ちクロスオーバー
Run or fight? A nail-biting, exhilarating crossover.
Are you chicken? 上等だ
Are you chicken? Bring it on.
余計なお世話 You can know the no order Clap your hands!!
None of your business, you know the no order, clap your hands!
上昇する鼓動とボルテージ
Rising heartbeat and voltage.
これぞ Roman of the man 駆ける熱狂のステージ let's get it
This is a man's romance, running through a frenzied stage, let's get it!
夢の 3$EVEN
The dream's 3$EVEN!
目もくらむほど Big Money, Money, Money
Dazzling enough to blind you, big money, money, money!
Go to the Hell or Heaven?
運命の行方は Nobody knows
Where fate leads, nobody knows.
SEVEN SEVEN Cherry
現実(リアル)は Heavy 泡のように消えてく Money, Money, Money
Reality is heavy, vanishing like bubbles—money, money, money!
Gimme Gimme 夢の 3$EVEN
Gimme gimme, the dream's 3$EVEN!
神様 俺様 My god, My god, My god
God, myself, my god, my god, my god!
Hey!! My life is gamble
Hey!! My life is a gamble.
そう Just believe 一度きりの show Come on everybody!!
Just believe in this one-and-only show. Come on everybody!!
Hey!! 弾けるパンパンのドル箱
Hey!! Overflowing coin boxes bursting open.
カチ盛ってこうぜ乗ってこうぜ揺らせ Shake your body!!
Let's stack it high, ride the wave, and shake your body!
灰になって down!! (down!!) 灰になって up!! (up!!) 本当も lose control
Turning to ash, down! Turning to ash, up! Truly losing control.
また go round and round!! 溢れ出すドーパミン
Going round and round again! Dopamine overflowing.
高鳴る心臓 on the beat
A thumping heartbeat on the beat
一網打尽を 一網打尽さ 当たれ！当たれ！一世一代 勝ち抜くGame
Wipe them out in one sweep! Hit it! Hit it! Win this lifetime game.
負け犬 Loser じゃ終われえない
Can't end up just a losing dog, a loser.
一攫千金 すべてを Bet
Get rich quick, bet it all!
ノーリスクな人生に興味は No
No interest in a risk-free life, no!
SEVEN SEVEN SEVEN It's like Heaven
飲めや歌えや Party party party
Drink and sing, party, party, party!
その瞬間 アラームのサウンド 夢だよ Game over
That moment, the alarm sounds—it was all a dream, game over.
夢の 3$EVEN
The dream's 3$EVEN!
振り返る足跡に 涙の跡が光る
In the footprints I look back on, traces of tears shine.
この胸の奥深く 刻んだメロディ
The melody carved deep within my heart.
I could not look back, you'd gone away from me
I felt my heart ache, I was afraid of following you
When I had looked at the shadows on the wall
I started running into the night to find the truth in me
狂い咲くー！
Blooming wildly—!
嵐吹く この街が お前を抱く
A storm is blowing through this town, embracing you
吹き抜ける 風にさえ 目を閉じる
Even against the blowing wind, you close your eyes
お前は 走りだす 何かに 追われるよう
You begin to run, as if chased by something
俺が見えないのか すぐそばに いるのに
Can't you see me, when I'm right by your side?
人波に 消えて行く 記憶の吐息
The sigh of memories fading away into the crowd
愛のない 一人舞台 もう耐えきれない
An unloved solo stage, I can't endure it anymore
All of you in my memory is still shining in my heart
すれ違う 心は 溢れる 涙に濡れ
Our passing hearts are soaked in overflowing tears
紅に染まった この俺を
Dyed in deep red, this me
慰める奴は もういない
There is no one left to comfort me
もう二度と 届かない この思い
These feelings will never reach you again
閉ざされた 愛に向かい 叫び続ける
Facing the closed-up love, I continue to cry out
お前は 走りだす 何かに 追われるよう
You begin to run, as if chased by something
俺が見えないのか すぐそばに いるのに
Can't you see me, when I'm right by your side?
紅に染まった この俺を
Dyed in deep red, this me
慰める奴は もういない
There is no one left to comfort me
もう二度と 届かない この思い
These feelings will never reach you again
閉ざされた 愛に向かい 叫び続ける
Facing the closed-up love, I continue to cry out
紅に染まった この俺を 慰める奴は
Dyed in deep red, there is no one left to comfort me
慰める奴はもういない
There's no one left to comfort me.
Oh, cry in deep red
おうちにいたって通常運転だい
Staying home is business as usual!
メキメキSAN値あがるんだ
My SANity score is shooting right up!
ピザ寿司うまいぽとてチップス
Pizza, sushi, yummy potato chips,
世界公認の引きこもり！
World-certified shut-in!
どうしようもないことばかり
Filled with nothing but hopeless things,
考えてもしょうがないから
There's no use thinking about it, so
コントローラー両手持って
Grab controllers in both hands and
木植えよ魚釣ろう
Plant trees and go fishing!
現実入れすぎと闇落ちしかねんよ
Too much reality leads straight to the dark side!
推しのSNSで潜って
Diving deep into my oshi's social media,
ステータス免疫力全振り！
All stats maxed out on immunity!
おうちにいたって通常運転だい
Staying home is business as usual!
長編全巻ジャーンってオトナ読み
Reading full series all at once like an adult!
ネトフリアマプラふらっふるおっぽー
Netflix, Amazon Prime, streaming all day long!
世界公認引きこもり！
World-certified shut-in!
ぴくしぶ絵師大回遊
Cruising through Pixiv artists' galleries!
ゆうちゅば更新ありがとさん
Thanks for updating your YouTube channels,
あっちゃこっちゃコンテンツを栄養摂取
Absorbing nutrition from content everywhere!
エンタメの灯は消えへんで～
The light of entertainment will never go out!
会えない日は続くけど
Days we can't meet will continue, but
いつかはいつか来るんさ
Someday, that day will surely come!
このバトル独りじゃない
This battle isn't fought alone,
我々はすでにファミリー
We are already a family!
Stay home! Otaku in the world.
See you soon in Japan!
I love my room.
世界公認引きこもり！
World-certified shut-in!
何がどうしようとでんぱ組
No matter what happens, Dempagumi!
全然全然なんも諦めない
Never, ever giving up on anything!
あーだこーだ知恵絞って栄養供給
Wits squeezed out for nutritional supply,
エンタメの灯は消しさへんで～
The light of entertainment will never go out!
Stay Home! うちにいよう
Stay Home! Let's stay inside!
Stay Home! Stay Home! ここがバトルフィールド
Stay Home! Stay Home! This is our battlefield!
巨大悪に立ち向かう
Standing up against giant evil,
光の戦士たち
Warriors of light,
「在宅」って名の剣で世界を照らせ！！
Illuminate the world with the sword named "Stay-at-Home"!!
天命は自宅警備
Our divine destiny is home security!
世界公認引きこもり！
World-certified shut-in!
ということで、ここまでありがとうございました！
So, thank you all so much for sticking with us!
めちゃくちゃガチャガチャしたステージでしたが、楽しんでいただけましたかー！
It was a super chaotic stage, but I hope you enjoyed it!
3周年記念ライブ！3周年記念ライブ！ありがとうございました！
3rd Anniversary Live! 3rd Anniversary Live! Thank you so much!
こんなにもね、愉快な、素敵なゲストさんたちと楽しく歌うことができてめちゃくちゃ幸せです。
I'm so incredibly happy to be able to sing happily with such fun and wonderful guests.
そして、ポルカも自分のソロをめちゃくちゃ楽しみました！そしてそれもこれも日々の皆様の応援支えてくれてるお前たちのおかげであります。
And Polka thoroughly enjoyed her own solos too! And all of this is thanks to everyone's daily support and all of you who prop us up.
もっともっと楽しいこと見つけていくぞ！そして一緒に走っていこうな！
We're going to find even more fun things! And let's keep running together!
この後もポルカは、年末年始、誕生日に向けてどんどん盛り上がっていくので、4年目も入っちゃってるけど、改めてよろしくお願いします！
From here on out, Polka's getting more and more hyped toward New Year's and my birthday, so even though we're already into year 4, thank you all again for your continued support!
また新しいオリジナル曲なんかも進行中です！はい！
We're also working on brand-new original songs! Yes!
今日関わったすべての人たち、そして画面の前のお前やざいぐん、本当にありがとう！
Everyone involved today, and all of you in front of the screens and Zaigun, thank you so much!
はい、ということで、またこうしてここで会える日を楽しみしています！
Right, so, I look forward to the day we can meet here like this again!
それでは、おまるポルカでした！おまるんポルカは終わるよー！おつぽるー！
With that, this was Omaru Polka! Omaru Polka is wrapping up! Otsuporu!
ぽぽぽ ぽぽぽ ぽぽぽぽ ぽぽぽ
Po po po, po po po, po-po-po-po, po po po
ぽぽぽ ぽぽぽ ぽぽぽぽ ぽぽぽ ぽ
Po po po, po po po, po-po-po-po, po po po, po
ぽぽぽぽ ぽ ぽぽ ぽ ぽ
Po-po-po-po, po, po po, po, po
ぽぽぽぽ ぽ ぽぽ
Po-po-po-po, po, po po
ぽぽぽぽ ぽ ぽぽ ぽ ぽ
Po-po-po-po, po, po po, po, po
ぽぽぽぽ ぽぽぽぽ
Po-po-po-po, po-po-po-po
ぽぽぽぽ ぽ ぽぽ ぽ ぽ
Po-po-po-po, po, po po, po, po
ぽぽぽぽ ぽ ぽぽ
Po-po-po-po, po, po po
ぽぽぽぽ ぽ ぽぽ ぽ ぽ
Po-po-po-po, po, po po, po, po
ぽぽぽぽ ぽぽぽぽ
Po-po-po-po, po-po-po-po
ぽ ぽー ！ ぽぽぽぽ ぽー ！
Po, poー! Po-po-po-po, poー!
ぽ 、 ぽぽ ？
Po, po...?
ぽぽぽ 、 ぽぽぽぽ ぽぽぽ ？
Po po po, po-po-po-po, po po po...?
ぽー ぽー 、 ぽー ！
Poー, poー, poー!
ぽぽぽ ぽぽぽ ？
Po po po, po po po...?
ぽぽぽ ぽぽ ぽー ！
Po po po, po po, poー!
ぽ ーー ！
Poーー!
ぽぽぽ …
Po po po...
ぽぽぽぽ ぽー ぽ ぽぽぽぽ ぽぽぽぽ ぽぽぽぽ ？？
Po-po-po-po, poー, po, po-po-po-po...
ぽぽ ぽー …
Po po, poー...
ぽ ！ ？
Po!?
ぽぽぽぽ ぽぽ ぽぽぽ ？
Po-po-po-po, po po, po po po...?
ぽぽぽ ぽぽぽ ぽぽぽ 、 ぽぽ ぽぽぽ ぽぽ ぽー ！
Po po po, po po po, po po... po po po, po po, poー!